Girls in my magazines are a lot nakeder.
我看的雜誌中的女孩多數都是裸體的
Oh, hey, Joey.
嘿, 喬伊
-Hey. -Listen, I need to ask you something.
-嘿 -我有點事要跟你商量
You know how my stepdad's in prison?
你還記得我繼父在監獄裡的事吧?
-Yeah. -Yeah.
-嗯 -嗯
He was supposed to get a weekend furlough so he could go to the wedding.
恩, 這個週末他本來有個假期的  這樣明天他就能來參加我的婚禮了
But he just called and..
但是他剛剛打電話來說...
Well, apparently stabbing lceman in the exercise yard couldn't wait till Monday.
嗯, 他在操場上捅了一個送冰的傢伙  他就不能忍到禮拜一嗎！
-So he can't come? -No.
-這麼說他來不了了嗎? -對
And so there's no one to walk me down the aisle. And..
這麼一來就沒人挽著我走過紅地毯了  所以, 嗯...
Well, I would just really love it if you would do it.
嗯, 我很希望你能挽著我
-Seriously? -Yeah.
-真的? -對
You've, you know, sort of been like a dad to me.
你知道, 一直以來我都把你當作父親一樣
You've always, you know, looked out for me and shared your wisdom.
我是說, 你一直以來都很照顧我, 和我一起分享你的智慧
I am pretty "wisdomous."
我的確很有智慧
So, what do you say?
所以...你覺得呢?
Are you kidding? Phoebe, I would be honored.
當然, 這是我的榮幸, 菲比
Oh, thank you.
哦, 謝啦
I hope..
我希望
I hope you know how much you mean to me.
你能夠瞭解你對我來說有多麼重要
Listen, I hope..
聽著, 我希望
I hope that you know..
我希望你知道......
I don't want you to see your father cry. Go to your room!
我不想讓你看到爸爸哭的樣子 回自己的房間去!
The One With Phoebe's Wedding
rainystar壓制iPod-MP4
Oh, no, no, no. Let your dad get this.
哦, 不不不, 讓你爸付吧
It's my wedding planner. She's driving me crazy!
哦, 是我的婚禮策劃人 她快把我逼瘋了
Hello? Okay, stop screaming!
喂, 嘿, 行了行了, 別這麼大聲嚷嚷!
Okay, so halibut.
好, 那就比目魚好了
All right, so salmon. Either way. I don't..
好吧, 三文魚也行, 隨便什麼都好
-It doesn't matter to me. -Well, it matters to me!
-我無所謂  -可我有所謂!
Well, I don't care. So you pick.
好吧, 我不在乎, 聽你的好了
Did you just hang up on me?
你剛才掛我的電話來著?
All right, look, I need you at the rehearsal dinner tonight at 1800 hours.
好了, 聽著, 我要你在晚上十八點整 準時到達婚禮綵排的現場
Okay. What time is that?
哦, 好, 那是幾點鐘啊?
You don't know military time?
你不知道軍用時刻嗎?
I must have been in missile training the day they taught that.
哦, 當時我在接受導彈訓練, 所以沒學到
Just subtract 12.
減12就行了
Okay, so 1800 minus 12..
噢, 那1800減去12
is 1788.
就是1788
-Six o'clock! -Okay.
-6點鐘! -噢
Hold on. Yeah? Geller here.
哦, 等一下 好, 我是蓋勒
No, I said it has to be there by 4:00. Goodbye.
不, 我說過了, 一定要在4點之前送到  再見
How hard is it to make an ice sculpture?
天哪 做一個冰雕有那麼難麼?
Harder than it looks.
比看起來難！
Wait. Ice sculpture? That sounds really fancy.
冰雕? 太隆重了吧
I told you, I just want a simple wedding.
我跟你說過我只想要一個簡單的婚禮就好
Please, honey, leave the details to me.
放心好了, 親愛的 一切都包在我身上
Now, I wanna make this day as special for you as I can.
為了你, 我會盡量把這一天弄得特別一些
I was thinking the harpist should wear white.
好了, 我打算讓港灣樂隊(the Harbours) 穿成白色
Harpist? My friend Marjorie is playing the steel drums.
港灣樂隊? 不是我朋友馬崔來敲鋼鼓的嗎?
-Oh, she backed out. -She did? Why?
-哦, 她退出了  -她退出了? 為什麼?
I made her.
我叫她這麼做的
Steel drums don't really say "elegant wedding."
鋼鼓和高雅的婚禮不太搭調
-Nor does Marjorie's overwhelming scent. -Hey!
-而且馬崔的體味太濃了 -嘿!
She will shower when Tibet is free.
西藏獨立之後她會洗澡的
-Hey. You look great. -You too.
-嘿 你看起來真美 -你也是
I'm glad we're having a rehearsal dinner. I rarely practice my meals before I eat.
我真高興能有這麼一次綵排, 我打算 在把這些食物吃下去之前, 好好跟它們演習一下
What did we say was your one gift to us?
嘿, 還記得你答應過 要送給我們的禮物是什麼嗎？
No stupid jokes, but I thought that was for the actual wedding.
不開無聊的玩笑, 我以為那只是在正式的婚禮上
Rehearse it.
先演習一下吧
Hi.
嗨
-Thanks for coming, you guys. -Oh, yeah..
-真高興你們都來了  -哦, 我...
I was.. I was going for a handshake.
我只打算握個手
That why your hand's against my crotch?
所以你把手頂在我的褲襠上?
-That is why. -Yeah.
-沒錯  -好了
So, Rach, where's Emma?
瑞秋, 艾瑪呢？
Monica made me send her to my mom's.
哦, 莫妮卡讓我把她送到我媽那裡去了
Apparently, babies and weddings don't mix.
顯然, 嬰兒和婚禮可摻合不到一塊兒
Are you still crying about your damn baby?
你還在為你那煩人的小傢伙哭哭啼啼的?
Phoebe, you got to keep the line moving. Remember,20 seconds per person.
菲比, 待會兒（在致酒時）你要說快點  記住, 跟每個人都是20秒
You see these clowns all the time.
你和這些傢伙天天見面
You must give me the name of your wedding planner.
你最好把婚禮策劃人的名字給我
I wanna throw a really tense party.
我真想把緊張的舞會拋開
-Hey, you're Mike's parents, right? -Yes, we are.
-嘿, 你們是麥克的父母吧? -是的
Our little ones are growing up fast, aren't they?
眼看著我們的小傢伙們都長這麼大了, 是吧？
-How's that? -You know..
-你說什麼? -你知道
on one hand, you're happy for them. On the other, it's hard to let go.
我們做父母的, 一方面替他們感到高興 但另一方面, 心裡又難免有點捨不得
How do you want to divide up the holidays?
你怎麼能想著把假日給分開呢?
I was thinking Thanksgiving at my place, Christmas at yours.
我在想感恩節在我家, 聖誕在你家
Who in God's name are you?
你到底是誰啊?
I'm not that fond of you either, buddy. I'm just trying to be nice for the kids.
嘿, 我也不喜歡你們, 知道嗎? 我是看在孩子們的面子上才跟你們客氣的
You know what? We have no idea what we're doing in the wedding tomorrow.
你知道我剛想起什麼嗎? 咱倆還沒有被分配在婚禮上的任務呢
I thought we'd be groomsmen. They would have asked us by now.
對啊,我覺得咱們會是伴郎 但都到這會兒了, 他們怎麼還不跟咱倆說呢?
When did they ask you to be a bridesmaid?
你什麼時候知道你是伴娘的?
-November. -I wanna say it's not looking good.
-呃... 11月? -我覺得情況有點不妙
-Hey, Phoebe? -Sorry?
-嘿, 菲比！ -幹嗎?
You haven't told these guys what they're doing in the wedding yet.
呃, 你還沒有告訴他們倆在婚禮上要做什麼呢
Well, they're not in the wedding.
哦, 那個, 他們不會出現在婚禮儀式上
What?
什麼?
Well..
呃
this is really awkward.
氣氛有點尷尬
Oh, and I can leave.
哦, 這兒沒我的事兒了
I'm sorry, you guys. But Mike's got his brother and his friends from school.
真對不起你們, 但麥克有一個哥哥 而且還有他在學校的死黨
So, you know, you were..
所以...
If it helps, you were next in line. You just missed the cut.
如果這麼說能讓你們好受一點, 你們兩個是頭號候補, 就差那麼一點
Oh, man.
哦, 天哪.
This is like figure skating team all over again.
以前在選花樣滑冰隊員的時候就是這樣
I mean, synchronized swimming.
我是說, 水上芭蕾
I mean.. I mean, the balance beam.
我的意思是, 平衡木
-Help me. -Football.
-幫幫忙. -橄欖球!
Thank you.
謝了
Oh, Phoebe, spit that out. That has pork in it.
噢, 菲比, 趕快吐出來 那裡面有豬肉
I thought the pot stickers were supposed to be vegetarian?
我記得那個砂鍋應該是全素的？
Yeah, I changed them. I sent you a fax about it.
啊, 是的, 但我做了點變動 我發傳真告訴你了
I don't have a fax machine.
可是我根本沒有傳真機啊
Well, then there are gonna be a few surprises.
哈! 那你可能會發現有一些意外
I can't believe we're gonna be the only people not in the wedding.
我簡直不敢相信 只有我們倆個不會出現在儀式上
-I know. I hate being left out of things. -And it's a wedding.
-是啊, 我討厭被冷落  -要知道這是一個婚禮!
It'll be weird if I'm not in it.
如果缺了我感覺會很奇怪的
-Hey, guys, how's it going? -Fine.
-嘿, 你們倆怎麼樣? -還好啦
We're sitting here, alone, doing nothing. It's our rehearsal for tomorrow.
這不, 我們正坐著呢, 就我們倆, 無所事事  我們在為明天做綵排呢
Look, about tomorrow, I've got a question for you.
嘿, 關於明天, 我有個問題問你們
I found out one of my groomsmen had an emergency and can't make it.
我剛知道我的一個伴郎出了點急事, 所以不能來了
-What happened? -Who cares? And..?
-出什麼事了? -管那麼多幹嘛! 所以...?
And I was wondering if one of you guys..
所以我在想, 也許你們兩個人中的一個能...
-I'll do it! -Me!
-我來替他! -不, 不 我, 我!
You both wanna do it? There's only room for one.
你們兩個都想做? 呃, 只有一個名額
Pick me. I look great in a tux, and I won't steal focus.
選我! 我適合穿燕尾服 而且我這模樣也不會搶你的鏡頭
No, Mike. No, no, you wanna pick me. I mean.. Watch.
不, 麥克, 不 選我! 我的意思是, 瞧!
You know, I really don't feel very comfortable making this decision.
呃, 我不太習慣來做這種決定
You know, Phoebe knows you better. I'm gonna let her choose.
菲比更瞭解你們 我會讓她來選
Well, if Phoebe's choosing, then say hello to Mike's next groomsman.
嗯, 如果是菲比來選的話, 你現在就可以跟麥克的新伴郎打招呼了
Oh, I will. But I will need a mirror..
哦, 我會的 但我要先找一面鏡子
as he is me.
因為這個人就是我
-Please. You're going down. -You are going "downer."
-省省吧, 你遜死了  -你更遜.
They say that on the figure skating team?
他們在選花樣滑冰隊員的時候 就是這麼說你的？
I wouldn't know. I didn't make it.
我不知道, 我沒被選上
You know I'm filling in for Phoebe's stepdad tomorrow, right?
明天我會扮演菲比的繼父, 你知道吧?
-Yeah. Yeah. Hey, thanks for doing that. -Oh, hey, my pleasure.
-知道 很感謝你能這麼做  -哦, 嘿, 這是我的榮幸
So, what are your intentions with my Phoebe?
那好, 你對我的菲比有什麼企圖?
-I intend to marry her. -Oh, a wiseacre.
-我「企圖」跟她結婚  -哦, 你這一拳打得還挺聰明
I understand you plan to support your wife by playing the piano?
照我的理解, 你似乎打算靠彈鋼琴來養活老婆
Isn't that kind of unstable?
這種工作好像不太穩定
-No more so than acting. -Strike two.
-哦, 跟演戲比起來還算好啦  -第二拳
You're right. She probably will support me.
你說得對 我可能需要她來養活
Hey, unless we move in with you, Dad.
嘿, 除非我們搬去跟你一起住, 爸爸
Strike three.
第三拳
You only get one more, Mike.
你只有最後一次機會了, 麥克
-Michael, can I see you for a moment? -Yeah, sure.
-麥克, 我能和你聊聊嗎? -當然可以
This was..
那真是..
weird.
太怪了
-Hi. -Hey.
-嗨 -嘿
What's with the face?
臉怎麼了?
That Mike has got no respect. I'm not sure about him.
那個麥克不尊重人. 我不知道他人怎麼樣
Wait, that's not him. There he is.
等下, 那個不是他, 他人在這呢
So? What did you decide?
怎麼樣? 你決定了沒有?
I decided to pee.
我決定...要去廁所
You have to choose one of us to be in your wedding.
你要在我們兩個人裡選一個來參加儀式
-One of the groomsmen fell out. -Oh, no, no.
-有個伴郎來不了了 -哦, 不
I can't choose between you two. I love you both so much.
你們兩個叫我怎麼選啊  你們對我來說同樣重要
Just not enough to put us in the original wedding party.
的確重要, 差一點就能參加原定的婚禮了
Such bitterness.
真痛苦
Best to keep that attitude in the seats.
最好把這態度留到婚禮
Come on, Phoebe. We both really want to do this, and it's up to you.
來吧, 菲比. 我們都想參加, 而且由你來決定
But I don't wanna choose. It's..
我沒法選 這太...
Okay, wait. Rach?
哦, 等一下 瑞秋！
Listen, I have a very special bridesmaid task for you to do.
呃, 我需要你作為伴娘替我選樣東西
Goody! What is it?
太棒了! 選什麼?
Well, there's a spot open for only one groomsman..
嗯, 現在伴郎有一個空缺
and you have to choose between Ross and Chandler. So good luck with that.
你需要在羅斯和錢德中間選一個 所以...祝你好運
What? What, what, what? No, I don't wanna do that.
什麼, 什麼? 不, 不要, 我不想選這個
I guess I have to find a new bridesmaid.
好吧, 我想我只好去另找一個新的伴娘了
I'll do it!
我來!
Okay, it's 2100 hours.
好, 現在是21:00
-Time for your toast. -Do I have time to go to the bathroom?
-到你敬酒的時間了  -我能不能先去一下洗手間?
You had a bathroom break at 2030. Pee on your own time, Mike.
你去洗手間的時間是20:30  要專時專用, 麥克.
In regards to the toasts, okay, you wanna keep them short.
關於致酒詞, 要盡量簡短一些
Nothing kills a rehearsal dinner like long speeches. Okay.
婚禮綵排的時候 沒有什麼比又臭又長的致酒詞更煩人了
You just get in, do your thing, and get out.
你要做的就是：上場, 幹活, 然後走人
Is that what you say to Chandler?
你跟錢德也這麼說?
It's 2101, and I am not amused.
現在已經21:01了, 而且我一點也不覺得好笑
Okay.
好吧
The bride and groom have a few words they'd like to say.
新郎和新娘要說「兩」句
Okay. Hello, everyone.
嗨, 大家好
And thank you all for being here tonight. So tomorrow's the big event.
很高興各位今晚能夠光臨  明天就是正式的婚禮了
Some of you might not know, but Mike and I didn't get off to the best start.
大家可能還不知道, 我和麥克的開始一點也不精彩
Yeah. My friend Joey and I..
呃, 是這樣的
decided to fix each other up with friends. So I..
當時喬伊和我決定相互替對方介紹朋友
Oh, okay. I..
所以呢, 我, 我...
I thought about it, and I fixed him up with my friend Mary Ellen..
我... 我當時仔細考慮了半天, 然後決定把我的朋友馬莉蘭介紹給他
who couldn't be here tonight, because.. It's not..
馬莉蘭今晚沒有來, 因為她...
It's not important. Well, she's in rehab.
這不重要, 她...
Anyway. So Joey said that he was fixing me up with his friend Mike..
總之, 喬伊說他要介紹他的朋友麥克給我認識
only he didn't have a friend Mike, so he just brought my Mike.
但他並不認識什麼叫麥克的朋友 所以他就把我的麥克, 呃, 帶去了
And.. And..
然後...
But despite, you know.. It got good.
儘管如此... 呃, 結果呢, 結果還不錯
I wanna take a moment to mention my mother, who couldn't be here.
好, 我想要在這裡用一點點時間 來緬懷一下我的母親  她今晚不能出席,因為...
Oh, God.
哦, 天哪
And.. And moment's over.
呃, 緬懷時間結束
So okay.. Oh, no, forget that.
好了, 呃... 哦, 這個就不說了, 然後...
I can forget that. Oh, this is funny.
我可以跳過這裡哦, 這個很有意思
Oh, but you need to know that to get that.
哦 但首先你得知道...
So.. Oh, well, okay.
哦, 好吧, 我...
I.. Okay.
我...
Okay, Monica, I can't do it like this!
好了, 莫妮卡, 我再也受不了了!
This is my wedding, okay? I don't want this..
這是我的婚禮! 知道嗎？我不需要這樣
Or this.. Or this..
或者這樣, 或者這樣,...
Okay? I just wanted a simple wedding..
好嗎？ 我要的只是一個簡單的婚禮
where my fiance can go to the bathroom any time he wants!
我要我的未婚夫能夠隨心所欲地上廁所!
-You know what? You're done. -What?
-你知道嗎, 你玩完了  -什麼?
You're fired!
你被炒了!
Cheers.
乾杯!
-Hey. -Happy wedding day.
-嘿! -新婚快樂!
Happy my wedding day to you.
哦, 也祝你快樂
Joey, listen, this is gonna be bridesmaid central, all right?
好了, 喬伊, 聽著, 從現在開始 這裡是伴娘的地盤, 明白了嗎?
We're gonna have hair and makeup in the bathroom.
我們要在衛生間裡面做頭髮, 然後...
I had to move a couple things in the fridge to make room for the corsages.
哦, 我要把冰箱裡的東西挪一下 給襟花騰出地方
Man! I wouldn't have had breakfast if I knew there was gonna be corsages.
噢, 真是的! 早知道有襟花我就不吃早飯了
Hi.
呃
About last night..
關於昨晚...
I know you're under a lot of stress, and..
我知道你壓力很大, 所以...
Well, even though the things you said were a little hurtful to me..
儘管你說的話讓我有點傷心
as someone who's never been fired before..
作為一個從未被解雇的人..
What about in high school..
高中時是什麼感覺..
when that yogurt store let you go for sampling toppings?
當賣乳酸的小店讓你做樣品招牌?
Everyone there did that.
大伙都這麼做
Yeah, but did everybody owe 3 grand at the end of the summer?
對啊! 但是不是每個人 都在暑假結束時賺了3000塊?
My point is..
我的意思是...
Well, I'm willing to take my job back.
好吧, 我願意復職
Oh, well, that's okay.
哦, 還是算了吧
I think you and I will do much better if you're just here as a bridesmaid.
我覺得如果你只做伴娘的話情況會好得多
Is that so?
哦, 既然你這麼說
Okay.
好吧
If that's really what you want, then here.
如果你真這麼想的話, 好吧 給你這個耳機
I give you the headset. I don't really wanna give you the headset.
我還是不太想給你這個耳機
I guess if you're taking over, then you should probably return these messages.
還有就是, 如果你要接手的話 你大概需要回復這些信息
This is a lot.
哇, 真不少啊
But I'm sure you can handle this. I have won awards..
我相信你能處理它們  我是說, 儘管...
for my organizational skills. But I'm sure you'll do fine.
我曾經獲得過組織技能的證書, 但是呢 我相信你肯定沒問題
-You've won awards? -I printed them out on my computer.
-你獲得過證書? -是我用自己的電腦打印出來的.
-Hey. -Hi.
-嘿  -嗨
-Where's Rach? -She's in her room. Why?
-瑞秋呢？ -她在自己的房間, 有事嗎?
I have to talk to her about this groomsman situation.
我要跟她談談關於那個伴郎的問題
I'm not gonna watch Chandler up there while I'm in the seats like some chump.
我可不想像個傻子一樣坐在那兒 看著錢德在婚禮上露臉
This wedding isn't about you.
這可不是你的婚禮
It's not? Then who's it about?
不是嗎? 那是誰的啊?
Well, it used to be about me, but now I have no idea.
好吧, 這婚禮曾經和我有關 但現在我也不知道了
My God, you're breathtaking.
啊, 天哪, 你簡直美得令人窒息
What do you want?
你想幹嘛?
You haven't by any chance chosen a groomsman yet, have you?
你還沒決定伴郎的人選吧?
Ross, please don't make this harder than it already is.
哦, 羅斯, 求你了 我已經很為難了, 你就別再添亂了
I'm not. I'm making it easier. Pick me.
我沒有啊  我是在讓事情簡單化, 選我!
Chandler said it's important to him too.
可是, 錢德也說這個機會對他十分重要
I'm sorry, did you and Chandler go out?
抱歉, 你要和錢德出去嗎?
Do you and Chandler have a huge history, huh?
你和錢德曾經抱過嗎?
Do you and Chandler have a child together?
你和錢德有孩子嗎?
If I said yes that would freak you out, wouldn't it?
如果我說是, 就會讓你發瘋, 是不是?
Listen. Listen.
聽著聽著
Whoever you pick is gonna walk down the aisle with you.
無論你選誰, 你要知道 你選的這個人將要跟你一起走過紅地毯
Now, I promise I won't say a word. But if you pick Chandler..
我可以保證, 到時候我一個字也不會說 但如果你選錢德的話
he's gonna be whispering stupid jokes in your ear the whole time.
他肯定會一直在你耳朵旁邊 嘀咕他那些無聊的玩笑
Oh, you are the lesser of two evils.
哦.....你確實強一點..
Yes!
沒錯
Don't say anything to Chandler until I talk to him.
先別跟錢德說, 我來和他說
-You got it. -Okay.
-明白了 -好
I cannot believe you played the Emma card.
真不相信你玩艾瑪的卡片
Oh, please. I was prepared to offer you my body.
行了! 我要把自己獻給你了
Oh, my God! And I didn't hold out.
喔 天啊! 我竟然沒阻止你
You know, normally, that would hurt my feelings..
你知道, 那通常都會傷我的感情..
but today, I'm a groomsman.
但是今天, 我是男儐相
Sven, I don't understand what you're saying. What is wrong with the flowers?
塞文, 我不知道你在說什麼  花又有什麼問題了?
"Lorkins"? What the hell are "lorkins"?
Lorgans? Lorgans是什麼見鬼的玩意?
I know.
我知道
-Hey. -Mike, if you were Swedish..
-嘿. -嘿, 麥克, 如果你是瑞典人
and you were saying the word "lorkins, " what flower would that be?
你用lorgans來代表一種花, 會是什麼花呢?
-Orchids? -Right there!
-蘭花(Orchids)? -真棒
That's why I'm marrying you.
我就是因為這個才嫁給你的
Hello, Michael.
你好, 麥克.
Joseph.
喬瑟夫.
May I have a word with you, please?
我能跟你說兩句嗎?
You wanna step it up there?
你想去那裡說嗎?
This is..
這裡真是...
great.
棒極了
Have a seat.
坐
Last night..
昨天晚上,...
I tried to welcome you into my family.
我試著歡迎你進入我們的家族
And instead, you disrespect me.
然而, 你對我很不尊重
I cannot allow this.
我不能容忍這一點
Are you rehearsing for some really bad Mafia movie?
你是在排練什麼劣制黑社會電影嗎?
More back talk.
還敢頂嘴
And yes, I may be borrowing a few lines from my recent unsuccessful audition..
沒錯, 最近我是參加了一次《榮譽家族》續集的試鏡
for Family Honor 2: This A-Time It's A-Personal.
我從劇本中挑了兩句
Joey, I kind of have a lot to do today. What do you want?
喬伊, 我今天比較忙 你到底想要幹嘛?
I want you to take this seriously!
我想要你認真一點
Phoebe is very, very important to me, okay?
菲比對我來說非常非常的重要, 知道嗎？
I wanna make sure you are gonna take care of her.
我要你保證, 你會好好照顧她
Joe, I love Phoebe.
喬伊, 我愛菲比
She's the most important thing in my life.
在我的生命中沒有什麼比她更重要
I'd die before I let anything happen to her.
我寧死也不會讓她受到任何傷害
That's what I wanted to hear.
這才是我想聽的
Because she's family, okay?
因為我當她是家人, 知道嗎？
And now you're gonna be family.
現在你也要成為家裡的一份子了
And there's nothing more important in the whole world than family.
在世界上沒有什麼事比家庭更重要
That must have been one lousy movie.
那個電影可真是爛得可以
That was me!
不是台詞, 是我說的!
-Hi. -Let's talk about this groomsman thing.
-嘿 -嘿, 我能跟你商量一下伴郎的事嗎？
If you pick Ross, he'll walk you down the aisle just fine.
如果你選羅斯, 你知道的 你們倆只能安安靜靜地走過紅地毯
But if you choose me..
但如果你選我的話
you'll be getting some comedy.
你可就有樂子聽了
Even so..
即便如此
I think I'm gonna pick Ross.
我想我還是選羅斯
Yeah, I figured you might..
沒錯, 我覺得你可能..
because of the history, and you used to love him..
因為過去, 而且你曾經愛過他..
and you guys have a baby.
而且還生了個孩子
Well, thank you for respecting my decision.
那麼就謝謝你尊重我的決定了
Let me tell you why you need to pick me.
我來告訴你為什麼你要選我
See, when I was a kid, you know, I was always left out of everything..
當我還是個孩子的時候, 無論做什麼 我總是被冷落的一個
and it really made me feel insecure.
你要知道, 這種經歷總是讓我缺乏安全感
I was always picked last in gym..
在運動場上我永遠都是被人家挑剩下的那個
even behind that fat exchange student who didn't know the rules to baseball.
就算是那個交換學生, 那個連什麼是棒球 也不知道的傻大個兒也排在我前面
I mean, this guy would strike out and then run to third.
那個傢伙一打著球, 撂下球棒就朝三壘上跑
It's just so humiliating.
真是太恥辱了
I mean, you know how it feels to be left out of things, right?
我是說, 你應該知道被排在萬事之外的感覺, 對吧?
-No. -No.
-不 -不
Anyway, if I'm the only one left out of this wedding..
總之, 如果我成為唯一一個不能參加婚禮的人
I just know that all those feelings are gonna come rushing back.
以前那些淒慘的回憶就會再次浮現在眼前
All right, fine, I pick you.
好吧, 我選你
Yes!
太棒了！
Make "groom" for Chandler.
終於有錢德的一席之地了  (Make groom for錢德, groom和room諧音)
Oh, my.
噢, 我的天哪!
No, we're gonna do it my way. Because your way is stupid.
不, 要照我說的做  因為你的辦法太笨了
All right, I got to go. I have another call, Reverend.
好了, 有電話正打進來, 我要掛了, 牧師
Hello?
喂?
-I'm glad we had this little talk. -Yes.
-這次小小的談話還算愉快  -是啊, 沒錯
And thanks for all the wedding night advice.
對了, 謝謝你關於洞房的那些建議
That didn't make me uncomfortable at all.
我一點都不覺得尷尬
All right, so I'll see everybody tonight.
好了, 就這樣吧 大家晚上見嘍
-Okay. -Bye.
-好 -再見
Did you guys know that there's a giant ice sculpture in the hall?
呃, 你們知道在走廊裡有個大號的冰雕麼？
Oh, my God, what's it doing here?
哦 天哪, 為什麼會在這兒的？
I guess it got sent to the billing address as opposed to the shipping address.
呃, 我猜是送貨的傢伙 把投遞地址和付款人地址搞混了
-What a pickle. -Oh, my God, everything's such a mess.
-哦, 真是個蠢貨! -我的天哪! 什麼事都是一團糟
Why is this happening to me?
為什麼這些事情會發生在我身上？
How bad do you wanna stick your tongue on that?
你們想不想用舌頭去舔舔它?
-How's it going? -Good.
-你怎麼樣? -我很好啊
I'm just getting some coffee so I'm alert for the wedding.
我來要點咖啡喝 這樣我能在婚禮上清醒一點
That's what I was doing too.
我也是這麼打算的
Well, you have fun tonight.
那好, 今晚玩得高興點
-You too. -Oh, I will.
-你也是  -哦, 我會的
Me too.
我也會的
Wait a minute. I know why I'm being such an ass. Why are you?
慢著, 我知道自己為什麼這麼得意 但你為什麼也這樣？
-I'm not supposed to tell you. -I'm not supposed to tell you.
-我不能告訴你  -我不能告訴你
Did Rachel say you could be in the wedding?
瑞秋說過你可以參加婚禮了嗎?
-Yes. -She told me that too!
-沒錯 -她也那麼告訴我的
I don't believe this. I played the Emma card.
真不能相信, 我玩了艾瑪的卡片
I looked into my soul.
我審視了自己的靈魂
You told us both we could be in the wedding?
你同時答應我們兩個人參加儀式？
In my defense, you weren't supposed to tell each other!
我的解釋是, 你們不應該告訴對方的!
Rachel, only one of us can do it. You have to choose.
瑞秋, 只有一個人可以參加婚禮儀式  你必須要選一個
You and me together again.
你和我, 我們又能在一起了
Rach, Rach? Knock-knock.
瑞秋, 瑞秋, 咚, 咚（敲門聲）
-Who's there? -I'll tell you at the wedding.
-是誰啊? -在婚禮上我再告訴你
Hey, I forgot my scarf.
嘿, 我忘戴圍巾了
I can't do this. I don't know which one of you guys to pick.
我做不來, 我真的不知道應該選誰
Oh, you haven't picked yet? Oh, good, because I had an idea.
哦, 你還沒選好呢 我倒是有個好主意
I thought it would be fun if the third groomsman was my family dog, Chappy.
我覺得如果由我們家的狗恰皮 來擔任伴郎的話 肯定很有意思
What? A dog? No. Rachel gets to choose.
什麼, 一隻狗? 不, 讓瑞秋來選
Wow, this is a tough one.
真是難以抉擇啊
I think I'm gonna have to go with the dog.
看起來我只有選那隻狗了
So, what you're saying is that the chef is at the Hamilton Club..
等一下, 你是說, 廚子已經到Hamilton俱樂部了
but the food is not? And the drinks are there but the bartender is not?
但食物還沒有送到？ 飲料和酒水已經送到了, 但男招待還沒有到？
Are you freaking kidding me?
你... 他媽的開什麼玩笑!?
How's it going?
怎麼樣了?
-Help me. -What?
-幫幫我... -什麼?
I want you to be crazy bitch again.
我想讓你做回瘋婆子
Really?
真的?
Please?
求你了
-You really want me to come back? -More than I wanna get married.
-你真想讓我回來? -嗯, 勝過我想結婚
Okay, people, we are back in business!
好, 夥計們, 我們回來了
Oh, God, I have missed you so much. Okay.
哦 天哪, 我可想死你了
Get your hair and makeup done. I'll take care of everything.
好了, 去做你的頭髮吧  這兒一切交給我好了
-Hey, what are you guys gonna do? -About what?
-嘿, 你們打算怎麼辦? -什麼怎麼辦?
The blizzard. I just saw on the news..
暴風雪啊 我剛看電視
it's the worst snowstorm in 20 years.
說這是20年來最大的一場暴風雪
They already closed all the bridges and tunnels.
所有的橋和隧道都關閉了
But the band and the photographer are coming in from New Jersey.
可是樂隊和攝像師還要從新澤西趕過來呢！
I don't think they are.
看來他們夠嗆
Looks like you're not gonna be in the wedding, either.
哈哈, 看起來你恐怕也參加不了儀式了吧
So sorry, Phoebe.
真遺憾啊, 菲比
-Well, the club lost its power. -The news said most of the city did.
-俱樂部停電了  -是啊,聽新聞說,市裡大部分地區都停電了
-Since when do you watch the news? -For your information..
-你從什麼時候開始看起新聞來了? -呃,告訴你好了
since they hired a very hot weather girl.
從那個靚女開始主持天氣預報的時候
I can't believe you aren't getting married today.
真不敢相信, 你們兩個今天的婚禮辦不成了
I know.
是啊
It's so beautiful out there. You always wanted to get married outside.
哇, 你們看哪,外面真的好美  你不是總想在戶外舉行婚禮嗎？
-Why don't you just do it on the street? -What?
-你們倆幹嘛不乾脆在街上結婚呢？ -什麼?
Well, look, it's hardly snowing anymore.
看哪, 雪幾乎已經停了
I mean, you couldn't ask for a more romantic setting.
我想, 沒有比這更加浪漫的佈景了
This could be the simple wedding you've always wanted.
這不正是你一直想要的簡單的婚禮嗎？
What do you think?
你認為呢?
I think I wanna get married to you today.
我只想今天就跟你結婚
Me too. Monica, do you think we could do it?
我也是 莫妮卡, 你覺得這樣可行嗎?
Affirmative!
贊成
Okay, let's get these chairs out here!
好！ 大家把椅子都搬出來
Gunther, hit the Christmas lights.
甘瑟, 把聖誕用的燈飾都打亮
Okay, who left the ice sculpture on the steam grate?
喂！ 是哪個傢伙把冰雕放在熱水井旁邊的?
-Michael. -Hey, you made it. Great. Chappy!
-麥克 -嘿, 你成功了, 太棒了. 恰皮!
-There you go. -Hi. Hi.
-對啊 -嗨
I know getting married in the street isn't what you approve of.
媽媽, 我知道在大街上結婚這種事 肯定不合你的脾氣...
No, it's lovely. The lights and the snow. I could look at them forever.
不, 這挺有趣的, 又是燈又是雪的  我怎麼看都看不夠
I crushed a pill and put it in her drink.
我剛才在她的飲料裡下了點藥
Come on, sweetheart.
來吧, 親愛的
You know, Chappy's too small to handle all this snow.
你們看, 恰皮太弱小了 它恐怕難以應付這一地的積雪
Someone has to walk him down the aisle.
到時候需要有人抱著它
-Would this person be in the wedding? -I guess.
-那麼, 這個人也算參加了婚禮儀式吧? -我想是吧.
-I'll do it! -I'll do it!
-我來  -我來
Chandler, hello? I mean, aren't you scared of dogs?
等等, 錢德, 你不是害怕狗嗎?
I'm not scared. I'll just take little Chappy and..
誰說我害怕 我只要抱著小恰皮 然後...
He can sense my fear! My throat is exposed!
它知道我害怕它!  我的嗓子都翻出來了!
I guess I'm in the wedding then.
哦, 那麼我猜 出現在婚禮上的人就是我嘍 哈哈!
He stinks.
它好臭
Level one alert! I repeat, level one, this is not a drill!
一級警報! 重複, 一級警報, 這不是演習!
We have a situation. The minister called. He's snowed in, he can't make it.
我們碰到難題了, 牧師剛才打電話來說 他被大雪困住,趕不過來了
-Oh, no. -Hey, don't worry.
-哦, 不是吧  -嘿, 甭擔心
-I'm still ordained from your wedding. -Really?
-我在你們結婚那會兒 獲得的牧師資格到現在還有效 -真的?
Yeah. You think I'd give up being a minister and pay to ride the subway?
是啊 你認為我會放棄牧師資格嗎？ 那樣的話我坐地鐵就不能免票了！
Ministers don't ride the subway for free.
部長坐地鐵也不免票
I had to read the Bible pretty carefully, but, yeah, we do.
我仔細研究過聖經的, 沒錯, 我們不用買票
We have to find someone else to walk Phoebe down the aisle.
Ok, 如果讓喬伊來主持婚禮的話 那我們還需要有個人來挽著菲比
I'll do it!
我來! 啊哈哈...
Okay, Mike and Joey, get in position.
好, 麥克和喬伊, 各就各位
Chandler, come with me.
錢德, 跟我來
Okay, Joey's doing the ceremony, and Chandler's giving you away.
喬伊負責主持婚禮  你由錢德負責
Oh, okay. Hi, new Dad.
哦, 好 嗨, 新爹
So you ready to do this?
那麼, 你準備好了麼?
Oh, my God. This is really happening.
哦, 天哪, 這一切都是真的
-Phoebe, I'm so happy for you, honey. -Thank you.
-哦, 菲比, 我真替你高興, 親愛的  -謝謝
I love you. Wait, wait! No hugs! The dresses!
我愛你  等等, 不要抱, 當心禮服!
-Oh, what the hell. -Oh, come on.
-管它的  -來吧!
-I love you guys. -I love you.
-我愛你們, 親愛的  -我愛你
Okay, it's zero hour! All teams execute on my count!
好了, 現在是0:00  各小組聽我的指令行事
Let's get this bad boy on the road!
我們開始吧!
Is it okay I want you to wear that headset in bed?
我想讓你今晚戴著這副耳機上床, 你不反對吧?
I have you scheduled for nudity at 2300 hours.
呃, 根據計劃 我的裸體時間被安排在23:00
Oh, yeah.
噢耶
Okay, Marjorie, hit it.
好了, 馬崔, 開始敲你的吧
-Jeez, Ross. You could've showered. -It's the dog.
-天哪, 羅斯, 你就不能先洗個澡嗎  -是狗身上的味!
Groomsman? Why are you standing there? Where's your bridesmaid?
伴郎, 為什麼只有你一個人站在這兒? 伴娘呢?
We've got a broken arrow! Bridesmaid down!
我們遇到情況了, 伴娘失蹤了
Oh, that's me.
噢, 是我自己
-Ready? -Okay.
-準備好了麼? -好了
Oh, wait. Oh, no. Wait.
哦, 等一下, 哦, 等等
Wow. Aren't you gonna be cold?
哇, 你不覺得冷嗎?
I don't care.
我不在乎
I'll be my "something blue."
我要做自己的「something blue」  （象徵新娘純潔的寶物）
-You look beautiful. -Thank you.
-你看起來美極了  -謝謝
My God.
天哪
Aren't you freezing?
你不冷嗎?
Friends. Family.
朋友們, 家人們
Dog.
狗兒
Thank you all for being here to witness this blessed event.
感謝你們能夠到場來見證這一場天賜的姻緣
The cold has now spread to my special place..
冷空氣已經蔓延到我「那裡」了
so I'm gonna do the short version of this.
所以我會長話短說
Phoebe and Mike are perfect for each other.
菲比和麥克是完美的一對兒
And I know I speak for everyone here..
我相信在場的每一個人都會和我一樣
when I wish them a lifetime of happiness.
祝願他們一生幸福
And may they have many children..
願他們有很多孩子..
who will one day avenge their family's honor.
能夠為家族的榮譽而復仇
How could I not get that part? Stupid Ralph Macchio.
我怎麼沒得到那部分? 愚蠢的拉夫.馬切奧
Right. Okay.
好
Who has the rings?
戒指呢？
Okay.
好的
When I was growing up, I didn't have a normal mom and dad..
在我成長的過程中, 我不曾擁有真正的父愛和母愛
or a regular family like everybody else.
或者和別人一樣擁有一個正常的家庭
And I always knew that something was missing.
我總是覺得自己缺少了些什麼
But now I'm standing here today..
然而現在, 我站在這裡
knowing that I have everything I'm ever gonna need.
我知道自己已經得到了自己所需要的一切
You are my family.
你就是我的家人
Phoebe, you are so beautiful.
菲比, 你是這麼的美麗
You're so kind. You're so generous.
這麼的善良, 這麼的大方
You're so wonderfully weird.
古怪的你是那麼的迷人
Every day with you is an adventure.
和你在一起的每一天都像是一次探險
And I can't believe how lucky I am.
我簡直不敢相信自己是如此地幸運
And I can't wait to share my life with you forever.
我迫不急待地想要和你分享自己的生命 直到永遠
Oh, wait! Oh, I forgot. And..
哦 等一下, 我忘了說
I love you.
我愛你
And you have nice eyes.
還有, 你的眼睛很漂亮
I love you too.
我也愛你
-Joey? -Yeah?
-喬伊	 -怎麼了
Chappy's heart rate has slowed way down.
Chppy的心臟越跳越慢了
Okay. Phoebe..
菲比
do you take this man to be your husband?
你願意這個男人成為你的丈夫嗎?
I do.
我願意
Mike, do you take this woman to be your wife?
麥克, 你願意這個女人成為你的妻子嗎?
I do.
我願意
I now pronounce you..
我現在正式宣佈你們...
husband and wife.
結為夫妻
I got married!
我結婚了!
Could someone get me a coat? I'm frigging freezing.
誰遞給我件衣服? 我快要凍僵了
-It really was an incredible wedding. -It was.
-真是場讓人難以置信的婚禮  -是啊, 的確
I kind of don't want it to end. Hey..
我真不想讓它就那麼結束  嘿
you wanna come in for a drink and a bite of corsage?
你想來喝一杯嗎, 還有一些襟花可以吃
I'd love to, but it's 2300 hours..
我很想去, 但現在已經23:00了
and I'm about to have the most organized sex anyone's ever had.
我現在要去 經歷一次有史以來最有組織的性愛
-Whatever happened to Ross? -I don't know.
-嘿, 羅斯呢? -我不知道
Maybe he hooked up with that hot girl he talked to.
剛才他還在跟一個辣妹聊天來著 大概兩個人搞在一起了吧
Come on, Chappy! Do your business!
快點, 恰皮, 拜託你快點解決了吧,
Make!
拉啊!
I did not sign on for this.
我參加婚禮可不是為了做這個